American Psychological Association Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Administration, 1918-1985 (Box 29-292)
  - Departmental Offices File, 1948-1984 (Box 132-290)
    - Scientific Affairs Office
      - Projects and programs (Box 254)
        - Task Force on Environment and Behavior
          - Subject file (Box 258)
            - Relocation, 1974-1976, undated
            - Social impact assessment, 1974-1975, undated (Box 263)
            - Solar energy, 1976, undated
            - Sources of research information, 1975-1976, undated
            - Space, undated
            - Technology assessment, 1974-1975
            - Transportation, 1973-1976, undated
            - Undergraduate curriculum programs, 1974-1975, undated
            - Workshops, 1974-1976
        - Task Force on Family Planning
          - Correspondence, 1973
          - Minutes and reports, 1973
          - Subject file, 1966-1975, undated (Box 264)
            - Abortion, 1970-1974, undated
            - Attitudinal studies, 1970-1972, undated
            - Bibliographies, 1971, undated
            - Contraception, 1966-1974, undated
            - Education, 1970-1971, undated
            - Fertility behavior, 1971-1972
            - Future of population, 1971-1974, undated
            - Human development, 1975, undated (Box 265)
            - Legislation, 1970-1971, undated
            - Limitation of population, 1970-1972, undated
            - Minority viewpoint, 1972
            - Psychological measurement, 1971-1972, undated
            - Psychology and population, 1973-1975, undated
            - Public policy, 1970-1972, undated
            - Research possibilities, 1969-1971, undated
            - Sex education, 1971, undated (Box 266)
            - Vasectomy, 1970-1972, undated
            - Workshops, 1971-1972, undated
        - Task Force on Health Research
          - Agenda, minutes, and annual reports, 1973-1975
          - Correspondence
            - Feb. 1973-Jan. 1974, (2 folders)
            - Feb. 1974-July 1975, (3 folders) (Box 267)
            - Aug.1975-Jan. 1978, undated (Box 268)
          - Miscellany, 1971-1975, undated, (3 folders)
          - Newsletters (Box 269)
            - Background material, 1974-1975, undated
            - General, 1974-1976, undated, (2 folders)
          - Questionnaire, 1975-1976, undated
          - Report (Box 270)
            - Correspondence relating to, 1975-1976, undated
            - Drafts, 1975-1976, undated
        - Task Force on Testing
          - Correspondence
            - Fricke, Benno G., 1975-1976
            - General, 1976-1977
          - Subject file
            - Book on testing and social responsibility, 1974-1975, undated
            - Competence Level System, 1976, undated
            - Convention proposal, 1977
            - Court cases (Box 271)
              - Correspondence regarding, 1970-1977
              - Various
                - 1969-1976, (2 folders)
                - Undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 272)
            - Educational Testing Service, 1973-1977, undated
            - Evaluation, 1969-1974, undated
            - Experimental Personality Inventories, 1966, undated
            - Fair employment bibliography review, 1957-1980, undated
            - Liaison with educational organizations, 1976
            - Mental retardation and the law, 1975-1978
            - Minorities, 1969-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 273)
            - Miscellany, 1965-1977, undated, (2 folders)
            - Monograph project, Division 16: School Psychology, 1976
            - Moratorium on Strong-Campbell Interest Inventory, 1973-1977, undated
            - National Association of Elementary School Principals/North Dakota Study Group, 1976-1977 (Box 274)
            - National Consortium on Testing, 1977
            - Nominees for Committee on Psychological Tests and Assessment, 1973-1977, undated
            - Responsible use of psychological tests, 1972, undated
            - Slossen Intelligence Test, 1972-1976, undated
            - Test bias, 1977
            - Test manuals, 1976, undated
            - Test standards (Box 275)
              - Correspondence regarding, 1972-1973
              - Statements, 25 Apr. 1972-29 Mar. 1973, undated, (2 folders)
              - Validation studies, 1967-1980, undated
              - Wonderlic claim and response, 1974-1976, undated
      - Subject file
        - Budget, 1975-1977
        - Commission on Behavior Modification, 1973-1974, undated (Box 276)
        - Convention, New Orleans, La., 1974, undated
        - Manpower, 1972-1974
        - Organizational affairs, 1974
    - Women's Program
      - General correspondence
        - Feb. 1971-Dec. 1972, (4 folders)
        - Oct. 1973-Sept. 1978, (6 folders) (Box 277)
        - Oct. 1978-Sept. 1980, (6 folders) (Box 278)
      - Memoranda
        - Sept.-Dec. 1975
        - Jan. 1976-9 Oct. 1978, (5 folders) (Box 279)
        - 10 Oct. 1978-Dec. 1980, (3 folders) (Box 280)
      - Administrative material
      - Agenda, minutes and related materials, 1972-1975, and 1977-1978
        - Drafts and proposals, 1978
        - Miscellany, 1978-1979
        - Reports, 1974-1979
      - Projects and programs (Box 281)
        - Task Force on the Status of Women in Psychology
          - Articles, 1971-1972
          - Background information, undated, (2 folders)
          - Codes for questionnaires, undated
          - Correspondence
            - Oct. 1970-Feb. 1972, (2 folders)
            - Mar. 1972-Sept. 1974, undated, (2 folders) (Box 282)
          - Minutes, 1972
          - Related material, 1972-1973
          - Reports, 1971-1973
          - Surveys, colleges and universities
            - 1971
            - 1972, (5 folders); (1 folder) (Box 283, Box 284)
            - 1973, (5 folders)
        - Women's Research Conference (Box 285)
          - Administrative and budget material
            - Budget
              - Correspondence, 1975-1979
              - Expense report, 1975-1979
              - Management reports, 1974-1979
              - Miscellany, 1975-1979
            - Contract, 1974-1978
            - Financial, 1978-1979, (2 folders)
            - Publication, 1970, undated (Box 286)
            - Recommendations for research, 1978-1979, (2 folders)
            - Reports, 1979, undated
            - Workshop material, 22-24 Mar. 1979
          - Correspondence
            - General
              - 1974-1978, (3 folders)
              - 1979-1980, undated, (4 folders) (Box 287)
            - Memoranda, 1974-1979
            - Publications, 1975, 1979
      - Subject file (Box 288)
        - APA copyright transfer forms, 1980
        - "Beyond Adolescence: Some Suggested New Directions for Studying Female Development in the Middle and Later Years," speech, 1981
        - "Beyond Therapy: Mental Health, Women, and Equal Rights," speech, 1977-1978, undated
        - "The Changing Roles of Women," 1980
        - Committee on Women in Psychology, proposal on rape, 1977, (2 folders)
        - Contraceptive behavior, 1979
        - Curriculum analysis project for social sciences, 1979-1980, (2 folders) (Box 289)
        - Division 9: Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues, 1971
        - Eminent women in psychology, 1981
        - Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 1964-1972, undated, (3 folders)
        - Equal Rights Amendment, 1978-1980
        - Federation of Organizations for Professional Women, 1981 (Box 290)
        - "Inequality and Women's Mental Health," article, 1981
        - Meetings, 1981
        - Mental health and equal rights, 1981
        - Psychological testing in population research, 1981
        - Psychotropic drugs, article, 1980
        - "Sex Roles, Equality and Mental Health," speech, 1980
        - Teenage pregnancy, 1981
        - Women in crisis, conference, 1980
        - Women in science, career workshop, 1977-1978
  - Miscellany, 1963-1982 (Box 291-292)
    Correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, budgetary matters, and miscellaneous material.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material.
    - Advertised personnel openings, 1979 (Box 291)
    - APA Employees Council, 1971-1977
    - Archives material
      - Correspondence, 1979-1980
      - General, 1980-1982
      - Library of Congress, 1963-1979
    - Board of Directors, minutes of meetings, 1979
    - Budget, 1978-1982
    - Central Office, 1979 (Box 292)
    - Cost/Benefit analysis, 1969
    - Executive Council, minutes, 1979
    - External correspondence, 1979
    - Organization of APA convention, 1980
    - Responses to letters by other offices, 1980
- Boards and Committees, 1920-1986 (Box 292-549)
  Correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, reports, agenda, surveys, graphs, charts, lists, proceedings, questionnaires, auditing data and other financial matter, drafts of publications, printed and near-print matter, and miscellaneous administrative and informational material.
  Organized by type of committee – standing boards, standing committees, ad hoc committees, continuing committees, joint committees, commissions, and joint commissions – and therein by name of board, committee, or commission, with further subdivisions grouped alphabetically according to subject or type of material.
  - Standing boards (Box 292)
    - Board of Convention Affairs
      - Convention Program
        - Abstracts, accepted, with cover letters, 1948
        - Correspondence
          - APA seventy-fifth anniversary, 1966-1967
          - Cook, Stuart, 1968-1969
          - General, Jan. 1947-July 1948, (2 folders)
        - Minutes and reports, 1947-1948 (Box 293)
        - Miscellany, 1978, 1982
    - Board of Professional Affairs
      - General correspondence
        - Mar. 1957-Dec. 1958, (3 folders)
        - Jan. 1959-June 1964, (4 folders) (Box 294)
        - July 1964-Jan. 1979, (5 folders) (Box 295)
      - Committees
        - Ad Hoc Committee on Mental Retardation, 1964-1965
        - Ad Hoc Committee on Psychological Archives, 1953-1965
        - Ad Hoc Committee on the Practice of Clinical Psychology, 1964-1965 (Box 296)
        - Ad Hoc Committee on the Practice of School Psychology, 1965-1967
        - Ad Hoc Planning Group on Role of APA in Mental Health Programs and Research, 1957-1959
        - Ad Hoc Task Force on Education, 1960-1961
        - American Public Health Association Committee on Public Health and Behavioral Sciences, 1958-1967
        - American Psychological Association/National Association of School Psychologists Task Force, 1979-1980
        - Committee on Academic Freedom and Conditions for Employment, 1964-1965
        - Committee on APA/State Association Relations, Minutes, 1979
        - Committee on Assessment (Box 297)
          - 1961-1966, (4 folders)
          - 1967, 1980-1981, (3 folders) (Box 298)
        - Committee on Legislation, 1965
        - Committee on Local Professional Groups, correspondence, minutes, and survey, 1965-1968
        - Committee on Mental Health Research and Programs
          - Conference, 1964
          - Correspondence and reports, 1963-1966
        - Committee on Organization and Functioning of State Associations, 1965-1967, (1 folder) (Box 299)
        - Committee on Relations with American Speech and Hearing Association, 1958-1965
        - Committee on Relations with Local Clinical Groups, 1962-1964
        - Committee on Relations with Other Professions Standards Project, 1966
        - Committee on Relations with Social Work Professions, 1965-1967, (2 folders)
        - Committee on Relations with the Other APA, 1957-1965 (Box 300)
        - Committee on State Examination Procedures, 1958-1962
        - Committee on the Practice of Clinical Psychology, 1965
        - Committee to Study the Relationship of Medicine with Allied Health Professions and Services, 1959-1960
        - Education and Training Committee on Subdoctoral Training
          - 1965-1967
          - 1968 (Box 301)
        - Interprofessional Research Commission on Pupil personnel Services
          - Correspondence, 1962-1968, (3 folders)
          - Meetings, minutes, agenda and reports, 1962-1968, (2 folders)
          - Reports and related material, 1962-1968, (2 folders) (Box 302)
        - Joint Commission on Mental Illness and Health of Youth
          - Correspondence and reports, 1959-1968, (2 folders)
          - Related Material, 1959-1968
          - Reports, 1959-1968 (Box 303)
      - Meetings, minutes, reports, and related material
        - Nov. 1957-Nov. 1960, (8 folders)
        - June 1961-Oct. 1965, (6 folders) (Box 304)
        - Feb. 1966-Oct. 1979, (8 folders) (Box 305)
      - State and regional file
        - Alabama, 1959-1964
        - Alaska, 1959-1962
        - Arizona, 1959-1964
        - Arkansas, 1960-1969
        - California, 1959-1968
        - Canada (Box 306)
        - Ontario, 1964-1965
        - Quebec, 1966-1968, 1976, undated
        - Colorado, 1961-1967
        - Connecticut, 1960-1967
        - Delaware, 1960-1964
        - District of Columbia, 1959-1967
        - Eastern Psychological Association, 1967-1968
        - Florida, 1959-1970
        - Georgia, 1958-1966
        - Hawaii, 1959-1967 (Box 307)
        - Idaho, 1959-1983
        - Illinois, 1969-1968
        - Indiana, 1959-1967
        - Iowa, 1960-1967
        - Kansas, 1959-1968
        - Kentucky, 1959-1968
        - Louisiana, 1959-1968
        - Maine, 1959-1967
        - Maryland, 1959-1968
        - Massachusetts, 1959-1968 (Box 308)
        - Michigan, 1959-1983, (4 folders)
        - Minnesota, 1958-1968
        - Mississippi, 1959-1968
        - Missouri, 1959-1967
        - Montana, 1959-1968
        - Nebraska, 1959-1964
        - Nevada, 1959-1967
        - New Hampshire, 1959-1982
        - New Jersey, 1959-1967, (2 folders) (Box 309)
        - New Mexico, 1959-1964
        - New York, 1959-1968, (3 folders)
        - North Carolina, 1959-1967
        - North Dakota, 1959-1968
        - Ohio, 1959-1967 (Box 310)
        - Oklahoma, 1959-1966
        - Ontario, 1959-1964
        - Oregon, 1959-1967
        - Pennsylvania, 1959-1968
        - Rhode Island, 1959-1966
        - South Carolina, 1959-1964
        - South Dakota, 1959-1962
        - Southeastern Psychological Association, 1966-1968
        - Tennessee, 1959-1967
        - Texas
          - 1959-1980, (2 folders)
          - 1981-1982 (Box 311)
        - Utah, 1959-1963
        - Vermont, 1959-1961
        - Washington, 1959-1967
        - West Virginia, 1959-1964
        - Western Psychological Association, 1966-1967
        - Wisconsin, 1959-1968
        - Wyoming, 1959-1966
      - Subject file
        - Agenda, June-July 1980
        - Alcohol, 1963-1966
        - American Association of Applied Psychologists, merger with APA, 1936-1953
        - American Association of Marriage and Family Counselors, 1959-1967, 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 312)
        - Association for the Advancement of Psychology, 1977-1980, (2 folders)
        - Biofeedback, 1977
        - Board of Directors
          - Correspondence, 1966
          - 1980 retreat, 1979-1980
        - Child custody case, Iowa, 1966-1967 (Box 313)
        - Committee on Mental Health Research and Programs, 1965-1966
        - Community mental health centers
          - Correspondence and reports, 1964-1966
          - Legislation and related material, 1964
          - Staffing, 1964-1966
        - Community Mental Health Planning Program, 1964-1965
        - Conferences on classification and nosology, 1965
        - Congressional bills, 1963
        - Crime and delinquency, 1965-1966 (Box 314)
        - Demography of psychology, 1962-1963
        - Election of division officers, 1968
        - Ethical standards of psychologists, 1963-1965
        - Forensics
          - Articles, 1960-1962
          - Clippings, 1960-1961
          - Correspondence, 1960-1961
          - Form letters, 1961
          - Newsletter, 1961
          - Questionnaire, 1960
          - Report and related material, 1961
        - Free speech movement, 1965
        - Health care workers cut, California, 1966-1967 (Box 315)
        - Health, Education, and Welfare Department, 1964-1966
        - International Society for Rehabilitation for the Disabled, 1959-1966
        - Karl Heiser campaign, 1967-1968
        - Legal precedents, 1958
        - Legislation
          - California State Association, 1960-1966
          - General, 1959-1966
          - Information on various state associations
            - Correspondence, 1965-1967
            - Meetings, minutes, and agenda, 1965-1967
            - Reports, 1961-1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 316)
        - Medicare, 1967
        - Mental Retardation Congress, 1961-1963, undated
        - Miscellany, 1956-1967, undated, (3 folders)
        - National Association of State Mental Health Program Directors, 1965 (Box 317)
        - National Society for Crippled Children, 1958-1967
        - Nominations for boards and committees, 1985
        - Office of Economic Opportunity, Head Start, 1964-1965
        - Privileged communication case, Arizona, 1967
        - Professional informational requirements for practitioners, 1966
        - Proposed animal research legislation, 1967
        - Psychologists against Proposition 14, 1964-1965
        - Psychology as a profession, 1966-1967, (2 folders)
        - Psychology in the states, 1964 (Box 318)
        - Reimbursement, Board of Professional Affairs position on, 1960-1961
        - Rogers-Hozier controversy, 1959
        - State and association membership, 1962-1970
        - State association officers, 1966
        - Training in community psychology, 1967-1968
        - United States Public Health Service, National Health Survey, 1963
        - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council, 1958-1964, (2 folders)
        - Youth Task Force, 1967-1968, (2 folders) (Box 319)
    - Board of Scientific Affairs
      - Annual reports, 1970-1976
      - Memoranda
        - 1976-1977, (2 folders)
        - 1978 (Box 320)
      - Minutes, 1967-1978, (2 folders)
      - Projects and programs
        - Programs
          - Accomplishments in Psychology, 1975-1977
          - Ad Hoc Committee to Commemorate the Founding of Early Psychology Laboratories, 1977-1979 (Box 321)
        - Projects
          - APA Museum
            - Correspondence, 1962-1978, (2 folders)
            - Miscellany, 1961-1972, undated
            - Wertheimer letter, 1977
      - Subject file (Box 322)
        - Alternative job settings, 1974-1975, undated
        - Behavior modification drugs, 1970-1972, undated
        - Bulletins, 1970-1982, undated
        - Convention, 1973-1977, undated
        - Drug abuse legislation, 1969-1972, undated
        - Education
        - General, 1971-1974, undated
        - High school curriculum, 1971 (Box 323)
        - Public information, 1972-1973, undated
        - Federal regulations on medical devices, 1975-1978, undated
        - Health psychology, 1974
        - History of the Board of Scientific Affairs, 1970, undated
        - Instructional programs, 1970-1975, undated
        - Instrumentation, 1968-1978, undated
        - Interboard Linkage Committee, 1981-1982
        - Monographs, submitted, 1974-1975, undated (Box 324)
        - National Research Act, 1974-1978
        - Neurological devices, classification, 1974-1979, undated
        - Newly Emerging Areas of Research, responses to Board of Scientific Affairs, 1973-1977
        - North Carolina Science Advisory Council, 1977 (Box 325)
        - Pornography and obscenity, 1970-1971
        - Regional laboratory proposal, 1975-1976, undated
        - Sunshine laws, 1975-1978
    - Board of Social and Ethical Responsibility
      - General correspondence
        - Dec. 1971-Dec. 1974, (3 folders)
        - Jan. 1975-Jan. 1979, (4 folders) (Box 326)
        - Feb.-Oct. 1979, (3 folders) (Box 327)
        - Nov. 1979-June 1980, (3 folders) (Box 328)
        - July 1980-Apr. 1981, (2 folders) (Box 329)
        - May 1981-Apr. 1982, (3 folders) (Box 330)
        - May-Oct. 1982, (2 folders) (Box 331)
      - Establishment, 1952-1976, undated
      - Memoranda
        - Apr. 1973-Dec. 1978, (3 folders)
        - Jan. 1979-May 1980, (4 folders) (Box 332)
        - June 1980-Feb. 1982, (3 folders) (Box 333)
        - Mar.-Oct. 1982, (2 folders) (Box 334)
      - Minutes, 1971-1983
      - Miscellany, 1981, undated
      - Projects and programs (Box 335)
        - Amicus project, Okin v. Rogers, 1980-1981
        - Association of Black Psychologists
          - Black graduate students, 1966-1973
          - Correspondence, 1968-1972
          - Miscellany, 1969-1970, undated
        - Committee on Equality of Opportunity in Psychology
          - Ethnic minorities and discrimination, 1973-1978, undated, (2 folders)
          - Student representation, 1973-1977 (Box 336)
        - Committee on Promoting Public Interest Activities
          - Correspondence, 1974-1978
          - Minutes, 1974-1977, undated
          - Miscellany, 1977, undated
        - Project Impact, Minority Affairs Consultation Program, 1972-1974, undated, (2 folders)
        - Psychology Assistance Project for Vietnam-Era Veterans, 1974-1979
        - Subcommittee on the Morality of Testing, 1971-1974, undated
        - Task Force on Criminal Justice (Box 337)
          - Background material, Apr. 1974-Jan. 1978, undated, (2 folders)
          - Correspondence, 1975-1979
          - Final report, 1978
          - Grant proposal, 1976-1977
          - Meetings and workshops, 1977, undated (Box 338)
          - Surveys, 1976
        - Task Force on Juvenile Justice
          - Background material, 1974, 1978, undated
          - Correspondence, 1977-1980
          - Minutes and reports, 1978-1980, undated
        - Task Force on Lesbian and Gay Male Psychologists (Box 339)
          - Background material, 1976-1980, undated
          - Correspondence, 1979-1980
          - Minutes, 1973-1979
          - Resource book, undated
        - Task Force on Patient Advocacy
          - Background material
            - Spring 1971-1977
            - Jan. 1978-Mar. 1980, undated, (2 folders) (Box 340)
          - Correspondence, 1978-1979
          - Minutes and reports, 1978-1980
        - Task Force on Privacy and Confidentiality (Box 341)
          - Background material, fall 1969-summer 1978, undated, (3 folders)
          - Conference, 6-9 Nov. 1974, related material, 1974-1976, undated (Box 342)
          - Correspondence, 1974-1978
          - Minutes and reports, 1975-1977, undated
        - Task Force on Psychologists' Negotiations, 1976-1978
        - Task Force on Psychology and Public Policy
          - Background material, 1978-1982, undated
          - Correspondence, 1979-1983, (2 folders) (Box 343)
        - Task Force on the Mainstreaming of Exceptional Children, proposal information, 1977-1979
        - Task Force on the Rights of Children and Youths
          - Background material
            - 1967-1977
            - Undated (Box 344)
          - Correspondence, 1974-1980, (2 folders)
          - Minutes, 1974-1977, undated
          - Summary report, 1976 (Box 345)
        - Vietnam, prisoners of war, 1971-1973, undated
      - Summary of activities, 1971-1979
    - Education and Training Board
      - General correspondence
        - July 1951-Nov. 1954, (3 folders)
        - Jan. 1955-June 1968, (6 folders) (Box 346)
        - July 1968-Dec. 1974, (7 folders) (Box 347)
        - 1975 (Box 348)
      - Committees
        - Committee of University Department Chairmen, 1946-1952
        - Committee on Accreditation, 1970-1972
        - Committee on Continuing Education
          - Agendas and related material, 1971-1976
          - Correspondence